good news doct table has introduced a
好消息Doct Tablet引入了一个
module called RGB primaries now this is
名为RGB Primary的模块 现在这是
a big deal to nerds like myself who have
对于像我这样的书呆子来说是一件大事
been waiting for agx like developing in
一直在等待AGX一样的发展
dark table for quite a long time so RGB
黑暗的桌子很长一段时间 所以RGB
primaries is a very useful tool that
初选是一个非常有用的工具
allows you to control the individual
允许您控制个人
primaries without breaking the overall
初选不打破总比分
balance of the image it's sort of
形象的平衡这是一种
self-explanatory the Hue sliders Slide
不言而喻的色调滑块幻灯片
the primary towards the adjacent
朝向相邻的初级中学
primaries the Purity sliders allow you
纯净度滑块允许您进行初选
to inser or move the primary towards the
插入或移动主映像到
acromatic point here's an example we
魔术点这里有一个例子我们
have a cie chromaticity plot of some
我有一张CIE色度图
image and if we reduce the purity of the
图像 如果我们降低图像的纯度
red primary the primary will move
红色主音主音将移动
towards the acromatic point just don't
只是不要朝杂技的点走
forget that this plot is a 2d slice of a
忘了这个情节是一个2D切片
3D shape and does not paint the whole
3D形状 而不是绘制整个
picture of what insetting or reducing
镶嵌或缩印的图片
the Purity actually does to the whole
纯洁实际上是对整体的影响
range when paired with something like
范围在与以下内容配对时
filmic RGB or sigmoid RGB primaries is a
电影RGB或乙状RGB原色是一种
very powerful tool that will greatly
非常强大的工具 将极大地
change how I develop my images in dark
改变我在黑暗中显影的方式
table however this is a tool that can
表但是 这是一个可以
very easily break your images so it has
非常容易打破你的形象 所以它
to be used with care in my opinion RGB
在我看来 要谨慎使用RGB
primaries should only be used to inser
主要数据应仅用于插入
or reduce the purity of the primary if
或降低主数据的纯度 如果
it's used before sigmoid or filmic RGB
它用在乙状结肠或电影RGB之前
so before the image is formed now if you
所以在图像形成之前 如果你
increase the purity of the primaries
提高初选的纯度
before the image is formed certain areas
在图像形成之前 某些区域
of the image will fail to attenuate
图像的亮度将无法衰减
correctly which will lead to a sort of
正确 这将导致一种
mangled image let's take this beautiful
残缺不全的图像 让我们把这张美丽的
amazing photo of a wall that is
令人惊叹的一堵墙的照片
illuminated by this strong light as you
像你一样被这道强光照亮
can see there's a bit of a yellow Hue
可以看到有一点黄色的色调
shift in that bright area we can fix
在我们可以修复的明亮区域发生了变化
that by reducing the
那就是通过减少
Purity however if we increase the Purity
然而 如果我们提高纯度 那么
you'll see that this area will begin to
你会看到这个区域将开始
break this does not increase the overall
打破这一点不会增加整体
oress of this color it only breaks this
这种颜色的颜色 它只会打破这个
area which is illuminated by light so if
被光照亮的区域 因此如果
we push it further this area will fail
我们再往前推 这一领域就会失败
to attenuate and simply break and this
使之衰减并简单地破碎 这就是
looks absolutely awful and this may very
看起来绝对很糟糕 这可能会非常
well happen to your Sunset photos for
我们会把你的日落照片
example or uh skin in harsh
打个比方 或者 皮肤很粗糙
light so after we inser that orange what
点亮我们注入橙色的什么
can we do to get some of that orange
我们能买一些橘子吗？
back that we've just lost simple
回来 我们刚刚失去了简单
duplicate the RGB primaries module and
复制RGB主要数据模块并
drag and drop it above our point of
将其拖放到我们的点上方
image formation in this case it's
成像在这种情况下 它是
sigmoid so now if we expand the rgp
所以现在如果我们扩展RGP
primaries that's above our formation
在我们队形上方的初选
point we can increase the purity of that
这一点我们可以提高它的纯度
orange without breaking this area this
橙色而不破坏这一区域
whole process can be demonstrated by
整个过程可以通过以下方式进行演示
using my favorite color chart we expand
使用我最喜欢的颜色图表 我们展开
the RG primaries and start pushing the
共和党初选 并开始推动
sliders towards the right you'll see
向右的滑块 您将看到
that colors break rather
颜色变得更不稳定了
quickly I don't even have to push it
很快 我甚至不需要推它
that far to completely mangle that blue
如此之远 以至于完全毁坏了那片蓝色
so if I go and tweak these uh
所以如果我去调整一下这些
values the way I like it and then
以我喜欢的方式评价它 然后
duplicate that
复制那个
module and push it above our point of
模块 并将其推到我们的点以上
image
图像
formation you'll see see that I can
队形你会看到的 我可以
increase the Purity without introducing
在不引入的情况下提高纯度
too many
太多
issues and lastly let's use a more
问题 最后让我们使用更多
practical example the blue
蓝色的实际例子
bar that everyone is so familiar with if
每个人都很熟悉的酒吧如果
we just enable a couple of modules
我们只启用了几个模块
you'll see that there's a bunch of
你会看到有一堆
issues in the top right corner it's got
在它的右上角有问题
that uh sort of spilled paint effect
那种 呃 那种溢出的油漆效果
which I strongly dislike let's quickly
我非常不喜欢它 让我们快点
jump to RGB primaries module and let's
跳到RGB初选模块 让我们
insert that blue until we are
插入蓝色 直到我们
happy um about there and if you think
很开心 嗯 如果你觉得
this looks a bit purplish you can always
这看起来有点略带紫色 你总是可以的
tweak the
调整
Hue like that maybe I'll push that back
像这样的色调 也许我会把它推后
a
一个
bit like so now this looks much better
有点像这样 现在看起来好多了
already already but as you can see we've
已经开始了 但如你所见 我们已经
lost a bit of that blue feeling that we
我们失去了一点忧郁的感觉
had before again let's duplicate this
以前有过 让我们再来一次
module push it above filmic RGB by
模块将其推到胶片RGB上方
holding control shift and just drag and
按住Ctrl Shift 只需拖动和
dropping now we can increase the purity
现在滴下我们可以增加纯度
of the blue primary until we are
蓝色初选 直到我们
happy like so of course you can tweak
你当然可以调整一下
this further but as a quick
这一步 但很快
demonstration I think this is pretty
我觉得这很漂亮
good let's take a quick snapshot of our
好的 让我们来一个快速快照
results and let's compare that to the
结果 让我们将其与
original and if you've reached the uh
如果你已经达到了
the limit of the slider you can always
滑块的极限 你总是可以
right click and just enter custom value
右键单击并输入自定义值
like that that's it a short video but I
就像这是一个简短的视频 但我
think we've touched a couple of very
我想我们已经接触了几个
very important concepts of developing a
发展一个非常重要的概念
photo with RGB primaries a big thanks to
照片与RGB原色一个很大的感谢
flannel head for making this module um
这个模块的法兰绒头
this is going to be one of the main
这将是
Tools in my dark tables toolbox for sure
在我的黑暗表格工具箱里的工具肯定
that's it for today but I'll see you
今天就到这里 再见
very very soon with some hopefully
很快
exciting news I'll see you then
好消息到时候见
bye
再见